Guide to the Consumer Reports. Arthur Kallet papers, 1917-1993 and undated RL.11774
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Arthur Kallet papers
1917-1993 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11774
5.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Arthur Kallet was an engineer and leading consumer advocate, co-founder of Consumers Union. The Consumer Reports Arthur Kallet papers include clippings, tear sheets, correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, book chapter manuscripts, reports and other printed materials that document Kallet's career in consumer advocacy groups including Consumers' Research and Consumers Union. Correspondents include Bernard Reis and Colston Warne. Topics include management benefits, organization and finance, labor relations, dealings with consultants and government agencies, as well as U.S. government investigations into allegations of communist links and Un-American activities during the Cold War era. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Book Files; Consumers' Research; Consumers Union.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Arthur Kallet was an engineer and leading consumer advocate, co-founder of Consumers Union.
Arthur Kallet was born in 1902 in New York. Kallet received a Bachelor of Science degree from the Massachusetts Institute of Technology in 1924. Kallet worked at New York Edison Commercial Department (1924-1927) and American Standards Association (1927-1934). Kallet served on the Consumers' Research Board to 1933 and as Director (1934-1935) before co-founding Consumers Union in 1936 and serving as Director (1936-1957). Kallet was Director of The Medical Letter from 1957 and was founder of the Buyers Laboratory in 1961. Kallet died in 1972 in New York.
Arthur Kallet was author of two books: 100,000,000 Guinea Pigs (1933), and Conterfeit (1935).
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Arthur Kallet papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Advertising Council records
Alvin A. Achenbaum papers
American Association of Advertising Agencies records
Cause Marketing Forum. Halo Awards records
John O'Toole papers
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Arthur Kallet papers include clippings, tear sheets, correspondence, pamphlets, meeting minutes, book chapter manuscripts, reports and other printed materials that document Kallet's career in consumer advocacy groups including Consumers' Research and Consumers Union. Correspondents include Bernard Reis and Colston Warne. Topics include management benefits, organization and finance, labor relations, dealings with consultants and government agencies, as well as U.S. government investigations into allegations of communist links and Un-American activities during the Cold War era. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Product safety; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- General Files, 1917-1993; 1
  - American Standards Association, 1933-1934 (Box 1)
  - American Standards Association--Tribute to Paul Agnew, 1954-1956 (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Paul Geogh Agnew (d. 1954), physicist and ;pioneer in the field of standardization. First Secretary of the American Engineering Standards Committee, precursor to the American Standards Association (later American National Standards Institute/ANSI)
  - American Standards Association--Tribute to Paul Agnew, 1954-1956 (Box 8)
  - Articles, 1932-1962 (Box 1)
  - Articles, 1927-1936 (Box 9)
  - Articles--Guinea Pigs Go to Market (People's Press), 1936 (Box 9)
  - Buyers Laboratory, 1960-1987 (Box 1)
  - Buyers Strike Committee, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Clippings--Beauty, 1932-1940 (Box 8)
    Print advertisements, pamphlets and other printed materials
  - Clippings--Beauty, 1933-1939; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Clippings--Food, 1934-1939 (Box 8)
  - Clippings--Food, 1934-1939; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Clippings--Health, 1932-1939 (Box 8)
  - Clippings--Health, 1934-1939; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Committee on Standardization of Domestic Refrigerators, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Lectures, speaking engagements, 1934-1939 (Box 1)
  - Lectures, speaking engagements, 1934-1937 (Box 9)
  - Medical Letter, 1958-1964 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1932-1993 (Box 1)
  - Personal materials, 1917-1969; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Personal materials, 1917-1975 (Box 9)
  - Photography research, 1924 (Box 1)
  - Regional Plan of New York, 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - Regional Plan of New York, 1930-1931 (Box 9)
- Book Files, 1932-1951 and undated; 2
  - 100,000,000 Guinea Pigs, 1932-1935; 1
    - Best-seller lists, 1932-1935; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Best-seller lists, 1932-1935 (Box 9)
    - Publicity, 1932-1934; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Publicity, 1933-1934 (Box 9)
    - Reviews, 1932-1933; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Reviews, 1932-1934 (Box 9)
  - Cost of Living (Manuscript drafts and clippings), 1942 and undated; 2
    - Appliances, undated (Box 2)
    - Dry cleaning, undated (Box 2)
    - Fuel oil standards and grades, 1942 and undated (Box 2)
    - Health, undated (Box 2)
    - House cleaning and cleaning agents, undated (Box 2)
    - Index and miscellaneous, undated (Box 2)
    - Introduction, undated (Box 2)
    - Keeping clothing clean, undated (Box 2)
    - Linoleum, rugs, carpets, undated (Box 2)
    - Removing spots and stains, undated (Box 2)
    - Saving clothing in the family, 1942 and undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Small household equipment, undated (Box 2)
    - Taking care of your electrical appliances, undated (Box 2)
    - Textiles, undated (Box 2)
    - Your personal finance program, undated (Box 2)
  - Counterfeit, 1932-1951; 3
    - Background articles, 1933-1940 (Box 8)
    - Background articles, 1932-1939; 2 folders (Box 9)
    - Correspondence, 1934-1951 (Box 2)
    - Publicity, 1934-1936 (Box 9)
  - Poison for Profit, 1932; 4
    - Manuscript drafts and correspondence, 1932 (Box 2)
- Consumers' Research, 1929-1960; 3
  - General Files, 1929-1960; 5
    - Consumers Advisory Board of the National Recovery Act, 1933-1935 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1936 (Box 3)
    - John Day Company, Publishers, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Magazine and newspaper articles, 1933-1937 (Box 3)
    - Minutes, 1933-1935 (Box 3)
    - Promotional materials, 1929-1935 (Box 3)
    - Tugwell/Copeland Food, Drug and Cosmetic Bill hearings, 1932-1935 (Box 3)
    - Vanguard Press, 1932-1960; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Strike of 1935, 6
    - American Federation of Labor correspondence, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Arbitration, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Board of Directors correspondence, 1935 (Box 3)
    - General correspondence, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Legal Defense Committee for strikers, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Organizations supporting strikers, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Strike Aid Committee, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Strike plan, statements, testimonies, 1935 (Box 4)
- Consumers Union, 1935-1964; 4
  - General Files, 1936-1964; 7
    - Ad Hoc Operation Committee, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
    - Board of Directors correspondence, 1950-1960 (Box 4)
    - Board of Directors Policy Committee, 1951-1953 (Box 4)
    - Board of Directors--Resignation of Kallett, 1956-1957 (Box 4)
    - Brady Report correspondence, 1956 (Box 4)
      Berkeley economist Robert A. Brady, was a co-founder of Consumers Union. He researched the economic impact of consumer testing services, which led to an examination of Consumers Union's practices and recommendations for improvement.
    - Budget controversy/Finance Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and documentation, 1936-1957; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Correspondence and documentation, 1955 (Box 8)
    - Kallet correspondence with Bernard Reis, 1952-1958 (Box 5)
      Bernard Reis, accountant associated with Consumers Union finances.
    - Labor Advisory Committee, 1937-1951 (Box 5)
    - Magazine and newspaper articles, 1935-1957 (Box 5)
    - Magazine and newspaper articles, 1933-1937 (Box 9)
    - Pension plan for management, 1951-1962; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Purchase of Mount Vernon property, 1953 (Box 5)
    - Rogers, Slade & Hill, 1954-1956 (Box 5)
      Management consulting firm, commissioned to advise on the Technical Department
    - Tax exemption, Internal Revenue Service, 1953-1957 (Box 5)
    - The Henry story, 1956-1957 (Box 5)
      Controversy concerning dealings with H.P. Henry/Peter Henry Associates, a consulting firm engaged by Consumers Union to provide testing services.
    - The Weinberg story, 1953-1957 (Box 5)
      Constroversy surrounding Consumers Union and its relationship with Sol Weinberg, a clothing consultant, and allegations of a conflict of interest impinging on CU's reputation for disinterest.
  - Un-American Activities, 1935-1961; 8
    - Congressional reports, articles, other printed materials, 1935-1960; 3 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and documentation, 1940-1961; 5 folders (Box 6)
    - Correspondence and documentation, 1935-1939 (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939-1952 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939 (Box 8)